なんで… うっ！
Why...?
なんで わからねえんだ！
Why don't you get it?!
もうじき お前の体は…➡
Soon, Orochimaru's going
to take your body!
大蛇丸に とられちまうんだぞ！
(サスケ)そうなったら そうなっただ。
If it happens, it happens...
子供のままだな… ナルト。
You're still a kid, Naruto.
オレにとっては 復讐がすべてだ。
Revenge is everything to me.
復讐さえ叶えば
オレがどうなろうが➡
If I can carry out my revenge,
it's no concern of mine
what happens to me,
この世がどうなろうが
知ったことじゃない…。
or to this world.
はっきり言うとだ…➡
Put simply, neither I nor Orochimaru
can defeat Itachi right now.
イタチは 今のオレでも
大蛇丸でも倒せない。
だが 大蛇丸に
オレの体を差し出すことで➡
But if I can obtain the power
to accomplish that
それを成し得る力を
手にできるなら…➡
by giving my body to Orochimaru,
こんな命 いくらでもくれてやる！
then I'll give him as much of
this life of mine as he wants.
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
Title
(ヤマト)話は終わりだ…。
The talking's over.
(ヤマト)ナルトとサクラ… キミたちの手前➡
Naruto and Sakura...
I didn't want to do anything rough
in front of you guys...
彼に手荒なマネは
したくなかったが➡
悪いが… もう本気でやるよ！
but I'm going to get serious now.
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
本気で って…。
What do you mean, serious...?
(ヤマト)大蛇丸同様
里抜けした者を➡
I can't just let those
who left the village in the same way
as Orochimaru run loose.
野放しにしとく
わけにもいかないしね。
(ヤマト)どんな手を使ってでも
彼を木ノ葉に連行する。
So I'll do whatever I have to do
to haul Sasuke back to the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉か…。
The Hidden Leaf, huh...?
お前たちは もういい…。
I've had enough of you guys...
終わりだ！
It's over.
大蛇丸…！
Orochimaru...
(大蛇丸)その術は
やめておきなさい… サスケ君。
Don't bother with that Jutsu, Sasuke-kun.
放せ…。
Let go of me...
(カブト)こらこら…。
Hey-hey...
大蛇丸様に向かって
またそんな口の利き方を…。
Don't talk to
Orochimaru-sama like that...
やめる理由はない…。
I've got no reason to stop.
今の暁の動きを
キミも知ってるよね？
You know what the Akatsuki
are up to, don't you?
(カブト)この木ノ葉の人たちには➡
We want these guys from
the Hidden Leaf
暁を始末しておいて
もらいたいんだよ。
to take care of the Akatsuki for us.
１人でも多くね…。
As many of them as possible...
他の暁に ジャマされると➡
Your revenge won't turn out well
if the other Akatsuki
get in the way, right?
キミの復讐も
うまくいかなくなるだろ。
情けない理由だな。
That's a pathetic reason.
復讐の可能性を
１％でも上げるためだよ。
It should increase your chances of revenge,
even if only by one percent...
Isn't that right?
そうだろ？
行くわよ。
Let's go.
あっ！
Once again...
《また…
また止められなかった…》
Once again... I couldn't stop him...
《オレは… よえぇ…》
I'm... totally weak...
Crying...
(サクラ)泣いたって… 泣いたって
サスケ君は 帰ってこないでしょ。
Crying won't bring Sasuke-kun back home!
I'm here! I'll get stronger with you!
私も いる。
私だって 一緒に強くなる！
We've got...
close to six months left, right?
(サイ)時間… あと半年近くは
あるんだよね。
(サイ)２人より ３人のほうが
いいに決まってる。
It goes without saying that three
are better than two.
それに ボクは 結構 強いからね。
Besides, I'm pretty strong myself.
Thanks...
ありがとう。
Now then...
さて…。
《これからだな…》
This is just the beginning...
(トントン)ブヒッ！
(綱手)そうか…。
I see...
はぁ…。
"Hidden Leaf Hospital"
(カカシ)なんですって!?
ナルトたちが サスケと？
What did you say?!
Naruto and the others fought Sasuke?!
(自来也)うん。
しかし➡
Yes...
But, their original mission was to...
アイツらの本来の任務は…。
そう あやつらの任務は➡
Yes, their mission was to capture
the spy Sasori sent to Orochimaru
サソリが大蛇丸のもとに送り込んだ
スパイを拘束➡
木ノ葉に連れ帰ること。
and bring him back to the Hidden Leaf,
大蛇丸やサスケの情報を
得るためにもな。
and to get information about Orochimaru
and Sasuke as well.
だが サソリのスパイ 薬師 カブトは➡
But Sasori's spy, Yakushi Kabuto,
大蛇丸によって すでに
サソリの術を解かれておった。
already had Sasori's Jutsu
broken by Orochimaru.
そして 大蛇丸は この機に➡
And it seems Orochimaru tried to use
this opportunity to kill Sasori,
サソリを亡き者に
しようとしていたらしい。
本物のサソリが すでに
死んでいることを知らずにのう。
not knowing that the real Sasori
was already dead...
大蛇丸と接触した ナルトは
感情を抑えきれなくなり 暴走。
Naruto made contact with Orochimaru,
became unable to
control his emotions...
and ran amuck.
ナルトは ついに ４本目の尾まで出し
暴れまくった。
Naruto eventually
released his fourth tail...
and went wild.
さしもの大蛇丸も
九尾状態のナルトと やりあって➡
Orochimaru did battle
with the Nine-Tails Naruto.
限界を迎えたのじゃろう。
Even he probably reached his limit...
ヤマトが ナルトを押さえ込む間に
姿を消そうとしたようだ。
It seems he tried to disappear
"Stabilize"
while Yamato was attempting
to control Naruto.
しかし ヤマトの分身が 密かに追跡。
However, Yamato's clone secretly
pursued Orochimaru.
ついに 大蛇丸のアジトを突き止め
内部に進入。
Finally, they found Orochimaru's hideout
and made their way in.
そこで サスケと遭遇し
戦闘になったらしい。
Then it seems they encountered Sasuke
and a battle ensued.
それで どうなったんです？
So... then what happened?
サスケは
相当 力をつけとったらしい。
It seems Sasuke has become
significantly more powerful...
(自来也)ナルトは
まるで 歯が立たんかったそうだ。
I hear Naruto didn't stand
a chance against him...
はぁ… そうですか。
I see...
まぁ そう落ち込むな。
Well, don't get so depressed.
ナルトは 九尾化のダメージで➡
It appears Naruto wasn't able
to show his full power
十分に
力を出せんかったようだし➡
because of damage from
the Nine-Tails Cloak.
それに…。
いえ。
And...
No. I'm not all that depressed,
you know.
それほど 落ち込んでるわけじゃ
ないですよ。
現時点では サスケのほうが上だと
思ってましたし➡
I figured Sasuke would be stronger
at this point in time...
それに…。
And...
(カカシ)
サスケとの差を自覚したことで➡
Now Naruto will be more fired up
for future training
これからの修業にも
気合が入る。
after having realized the difference
between Sasuke and himself.
でしょう？
Right?
フン だのう。
Right.
まぁ 今回は
無事に帰ってきただけで➡
Well, I guess we should be happy
they made it back safe.
よしとしましょう。
(ホムラ)ナルトが 無事に帰ってきたのは
幸運じゃったな。
It's fortunate that Naruto
was able to make it back safely.
(コハル)しかし 任務には
不測の事態がつきものとはいえ➡
However, although unexpected situations
are an inevitable part of missions...
まさか 大蛇丸と
やりあうことになるとは。
I never thought he would end up
doing battle with Orochimaru...
(コハル)こういうことがあるから➡
And here, it's best to keep Naruto
in the village
ナルトは 里に とどめておいたほうが
よいのに…。
because things like this
end up happening...
(ホムラ)あの頑固者が 簡単に
意見を曲げるとは思えんしな。
I don't think that hard-head
would depart from his opinions so easily.
う～ん…。
はぁ…。
…で？
オレたちは あきらめねえ。
So?
We aren't giving up!
フッ では お前たちには
すぐ 次の任務を言い渡す。
Okay, I will issue
your next mission immediately.
おって連絡があるまで
自宅待機。
Stand by at home until I contact you!
おう！
Right!
Hey, Sakura.
Let's go on a date together.
なぁ サクラちゃん
このまま ２人でデートしようか。
Have you forgotten what
Tsunade-sama said just now?
アンタ たった今 綱手様に
言われたこと 忘れたの？
Huh?! What'd she say again?
あ？ 何だっけ？
We're supposed to stand by at home
私たち カカシ班は 次の任務が
決まるまで 自宅待機でしょ？
until Team Kakashi's next mission
has been determined, right?!
あぁ ちょっとだけなら
ばれねえってばよ。
What? She won't find out if
we just go out for a little while!
(サクラ)デートしたいなら
１人ですれば？
Why don't you go by yourself
if you want to go out on a date?
I won't be able to
go on a date by myself.
いや １人じゃできねえってばよ。
By the way, what about Sai's activity?
(綱手)ところで サイの動きは？
Yes. You were right
to be concerned, Tsunade-sama.
はい 綱手様が
心配されていたとおり➡
ダンゾウから
特別任務を与えられていました。
Danzo gave him a special mission.
特別任務？
A special mission?!
《シズネ : やはり…》
I knew it...
(ヤマト)サイは ダンゾウの指示で
暗部として 任務をこなしつつ➡
It seems Sai was put in charge
of undercover work,
dealing with potential risks
to the Hidden Leaf
木ノ葉に対する危険人物の➡
while carrying out his mission as
諜報活動 および 処理に
当たっていたようです。
an Anbu Black Ops member
under Danzo's direction.
サイが 今回
ボクたち カカシ班に合流した目的は➡
Sai's purpose for joining us in
Team Kakashi was to eliminate Sasuke,
who is to become the new vessel
for Orochimaru,
木ノ葉が もっとも注意すべき人物
大蛇丸…。
the individual of most concern
to the Hidden Leaf.
その大蛇丸の 新たなる肉体
サスケを葬ることだった。
What?!
えっ!?
フン… 食えない男だと
思っていたが。
I figured he was a crafty guy...
方法は 武闘派路線の
主導者だけあって 強引だが➡
As would be expected of the leader
of a hard-line military faction,
his actions are strong-armed.
But our protective feelings
for the Hidden Leaf are the same, huh...?
木ノ葉を思う気持は
ひとつということか。
Are you talking about Danzo?
それは ダンゾウのことを
おっしゃっているのですか？
ん？ そうだが…。
Yes, I am...
では 結論は これをご覧に
なってからにしてもらえますか。
Then could you hold off on
your conclusions until you see this?
(綱手)これは？
What's this?
Danzo gave this to Sai as
a gift for Orochimaru
ダンゾウが 大蛇丸との接触を
円滑に進めるために➡
サイに持たせた
大蛇丸への手土産です。
in order for the contact with Orochimaru
to proceed smoothly.
Wh-What's this?!
こ… これは！
暗部の構成員リスト！
It's a list of Anbu Black Ops members!
《クソ… ダンゾウのヤツ！
Damn it! That jerk, Danzo!
極秘ファイルの中から
リストを どうやって手に入れた!?》
How did he get the list from
the classified files...?
あの 綱手様…。
Um... Tsunade-sama...
Shizune! Tighten security at
the classified files storehouse
シズネ！ 極秘ファイル倉庫への
警備の強化 および➡
and change the deciphering codes
for the files. Quickly!
ファイルの解読暗号の変更を急げ！
あ… はい！
Y-Yes ma'am!
Right now!
今すぐだ！
あひぃ～！
アハハハハ…。
Damn it! That sly old dog...
クソ！ あのタヌキじじい…
どこまでいっても 食えないヤツだ。
He's always the crafty one!
At a time when the outside
of the village
(綱手)大蛇丸 暁と
里の外が騒がしいってときに➡
is in an uproar with Orochimaru
and the Akatsuki...
I never thought I'd have to be concerned
about trouble inside  the village...
里内部のごたごたまで
考えなきゃならんとは…。
これでは 先ほどの サイの申し入れ
慎重に考えざるをえんな。
Now I'll be forced to consider Sai's
earlier proposal with caution.
In that case...
それでしたら…。
ん…？
(ダンゾウ)特別任務をしくじるとは…。
お前らしくないな。
I never thought you'd fail
the special mission...
That's very unlike you...
(サイ)ひとつ お願いがございます。
I have a favor to ask.
A favor, you say?
(ダンゾウ)願い… だと？
(サイ)はい。
Yes.
この名のまま しばらく➡
Could you keep me in Team Kakashi
under this name for a while?
カカシ班に身を置かせては
いただけないでしょうか？
《この笑い顔は…》
That smile on his face...
(ダンゾウ)その話なら
綱手からも受けている。
I've already taken that
up with Tsunade.
But you understand that emotions
create hate, don't you, Sai?
しかし… わかっているな？ サイ。
感情は 憎しみを作り出す。 そして
憎しみは 戦いを作り出すものだ。
And hate creates battles.
Bonds of hatred with
my older brother...
((兄との憎しみっていう
つながりがな))
That might be so.
(サイ)そうかもしれませんね。
《でも…》
But...
He's the person who acknowledged
me more than anyone else.
((アイツは 誰よりも オレのことを
認めてくれた１人だ。
サスケは オレの友達だ。
Sasuke is my friend.
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make.
(やっとできた 大切なつながりだ))
"Comrade"
((お前 「仲間」って言葉
知ってっか？
Don't you know
what the word comrade is?
Of course, I do.
What of it?
(もちろん 知ってますが…
それが 何か？))
Hey! Sai!
≪お～い サイ！
次の任務の
打ち合わせだってばよ！
We're having a meeting about
our next mission!
Hurry up, man!
≪早くしろってばよ！
(サイ)あぁ 今 行くよ。
Right, I'm coming.
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
sora wa haruka
kumo wa nagarete
Far, far, far away,
beyond the horizon.
tooku tooku tooku
ni kogaretemo
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
doko o mezashite boku
wa fumidasu no ka
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
mayoi o ima
furikitte
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
nigeba no nai
unmei demo
I'm searching
for tomorrow.
asu o sagashite
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
Your prayer will
be granted,
motomeru nara
woah woah
Because the light
you seek lies there.
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
たっだいま…。
フゥ…。
Awaken the
beast within!
mezamero
yasei
Hmph,
It's you...
At last,
they meet again.
Finally.
Next Episode
(カカシ)はいは～い！ 写真撮るから
みんな ちゃんとして。
I heard about everything from Yamato.
And I heard about Sasuke, too.
なんで オレ様が コイツなんかと➡
We don't have time.
一緒に写らなきゃ
いけねえんだってばよ！
And yet, we can't bring Sasuke back
with our power right now.
こっちのセリフだ うすらトンカチ！
なっ… なんだとぉ！
The speed of Sasuke-kun's development
was extraordinary.
まぁまぁ… これ 決まりだから。
According to Tsunade-sama,
でも 嬉しいなぁ！ サスケ君と
一緒に写れるなんて！
there's a possibility they're using
Forbidden Jutsu and perhaps drugs.
Then we just have to rapidly
get more powerful.
オレも！ オレも！ サクラちゃんと
写れて 超嬉しいってば！
But how do we do that...?
先生… ナルトは外してください。
Well, I wasn't just lying here
not thinking about anything.
ガ～ン… そんなぁ…。
フン…。
Nightmare
笑うな！
あん？
Next time: "Nightmare"
(カカシ)いい加減にしろ ２人とも。
写真屋さんも困ってるでしょ。
I'm home...
(カカシ)ほら… これ 残るんだから
笑って 笑って！
(カカシ)はい！ じゃあ
お願いしま～す！
Okay now.
We're going to take a picture,
so get it together you guys.
Why do I have to be in
the picture with him?
That's my line, useless.
Say what?!
Now, now.
It's customary.
But I'm so glad I get to be
in the picture with Sasuke-kun.
Me, too! Me, too!
I'm totally glad I get to be in
the picture with you, Sakura-chan.
Sensei, please leave Naruto
out of the picture.
No way!
Don't laugh!
Huh?
Knock it off, the both of you.
Hey, you guys are annoying
the photographer.
Hey, this is going to be preserved,
so smile.
Okay, then...
We're ready.